Nandini Morla

Full-stack Web Developer/SEO Consultant

+1(385) 464-9601, nandinimorla2520@gmail.com, linkedin.com/nandinimorla/, bit.ly/nandinimorla

Experienced Software Developer specializing in web applications(front-end & back-end). Excellent problem-solving and analytical skills, with the ability to quickly grasp complex technical concepts and provide innovative solutions. Strong communication and interpersonal skills, with the ability to effectively collaborate with team members. Worked on SEO, site audits, backlinking and keyword gaps.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, TypeScript, Ajax, XML, Java, C/C++, Python, SQL. **Libraries & Frameworks**: Node.js, Jquery, Ajax, Django,Express.js, React.js,Vue.js, Angular,numpy, matplotlib, pandas. **Core Competencies**: Data Structures & Algorithms, Git, Linux, Object Oriented Programming, ML, Deep Learning, Gen AI. **Database, Version Control**: Github, Babel, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle.

Tools: Wordpress, Wix.com, Webflow, Semrush, Google search console, Yoast SEO, ahrefs, backlinking techniques, keywords gap.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Tiny Archives Remote, USA

Computer Science Intern

June 2024 – Present

- Developed front-end for Tiny Archives official website using React and Tailwind CSS, resulting in a **40% improvement in user experience**.
- Implemented user verification and validation using AWS Cognito to enhance security measures.
- Created captivating images using Adobe Illustrator to increase user engagement on the website.
- Developing a chatbot named Rosie for the FACTool using NLP and Langchain to automate customer interactions.

Power Changes Lives

Remote, USA

Web Developer and Designer Intern

April 2024- June 2024

- Pioneered the design of a cutting-edge front-end interface for a 360-degree photobooth project, achieving a 30% increase in user engagement through captivating home pages, dynamic headers, and hamburger menus.
- Redesigned the Power Changes Lives website to enhance user interaction and navigation efficiency, resulting in a **25% improvement in user interactions**.

SUNY New Paltz, Department of Science & Engineering

New Paltz, USA

Teaching Assistant, Operating Systems

January 2023-May 2024

- I assisted in teaching Unix commands, Linux and operating systems concepts to undergraduate students and Conducted weekly tutorials, and lab sessions to practically show the real-time working of paging, segmentation, deadlocks, memory allocations etc.
- Evaluated the lab reports and assigned the grades based on students' lab sessions.

Websites

Interesting Blogs About SEO

• A website developed Developed on Webflow, offers insightful articles and guides tailored to boost your website's visibility and organic search traffic.

EDUCATION

PUBLICATIONS

<u>Face Mask Detection using Machine Learning Techniques</u> - IEEE Paper Publication. <u>Blog On Essential Tips for SEO</u> - Webflow.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Teaching assistant for all four semesters of the Master's Degree Program.
- Awarded the Merit Outstanding Student award in the Master's Program.